{
  "mcqs": [
    {
      "question": "<p> SELECT __________FROM instructor WHERE dept name= ’Comp. Sci.’; Which of the following should be used to find the mean of the salary ?</p>",
      "options": [
        "a) Mean(salary)",
        "b) Avg(salary)",
        "c) Sum(salary)",
        "d) Count(salary)"
      ],
      "answer": "B"
    },
    {
      "question": "<p>  A Boolean data type that can take values ________</p>",
      "options": [
        "a) False, and 1",
        "b) True, and 0",
        "c) True, False, and Null",
        "d) True, False, and Unknown"
      ],
      "answer": "B"
    },
    {
      "question": "<p> Which of the following is not an integrity constraint?</p>",
      "options": [
        "a) Not null",
        "b) Positive",
        "c) Unique",
        "d) Check ‘predicate’"
      ],
      "answer": "B"
    },
    {
      "question": "<p> Which of the following is a part of the Oracle database system?</p>",
      "options": [
        "a) Free lists",
        "b) Front end",
        "c) Network",
        "d) None of the above Answer"
      ],
      "answer": "B"
    },
    {
      "question": "<p>The number of attributes in a relation is called its ----- </p>",
      "options": ["a) row", "b) column", "c) degree", "d) None of the above "],
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "question": "<p>Which of the following machine learning algorithm can be used for imputing missing values of both categorical and continuous variables?</p>",
      "options": [
        "a) K-NN",
        "b) Linear Regression",
        "c)  Logistic Regression ",
        " "
      ],
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "question": "<p>Which of the following statements is true for k-NN classifiers?</p>",
      "options": [
        "a)The classification accuracy is better with larger values of k",
        "b) The decision boundary is smoother with smaller values of k",
        "c) The decision boundary is linear",
        "d) k-NN does not require an explicit training step"
      ],
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "question": "<p>Which search method takes less memory?</p>",
      "options": [
        "a)Depth-FirstSearch",
        "b)Breadth-Firstsearch",
        "c)LinearSearch",
        "d)Optimalsearch"
      ],
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "question": "<p>Which of the following is NOT supervised learning?</p>",
      "options": [
        "a) PCA",
        "b) Decision Tree",
        "c) Linear Regression",
        "d) Naive Bayesian"
      ],
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "question": "<p>Elements in an array are accessed ------------</p>",
      "options": [
        "a) Randomly",
        "b) Sequentially",
        "c) Exponentially",
        "d) Logarithmically"
      ],
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "question": "<p>What does the following function do for a given linked list with first node as head? Void fun1(struct node*head) { if(head == NULL) return; fun1(head->next); printf(“%d”,head->data); }</P>",
      "options": [
        "a) Print all nodes of linked lists",
        "b) Prints all nodes of linked list in reverse order",
        "c) Print alternate nodes of linked list",
        "d) Prints alternate nodes in reverse order"
      ],
      "answer": "B"
    },
    {
      "question": "<p>Which of these is not an application of linked list?</p>",
      "options": [
        "a)To implement file system ",
        "b) For seprate chaining in hash-table",
        "c) To implement non-binary tree",
        "d) Random access of element"
      ],
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "question": "<p> What is the output of the following program? #include<iostream>  using namespace std; main() { int i = 1, j = 2, k = 3, r;  r = (i, j, k); cout<<r<<endl; }</p>",
      "options": ["a) -1", "b) -2", "c) -3", "d) Compile error"],
      "answer": "C"
    },
    {
      "question": "<p> What is the output of the following program? #include<iostream> using namespace std; main() { int *p = new int; delete p; delete p; cout<<Done</p>",
      "options": [
        "a) Done",
        "b) Compile error",
        "c) Runtime error",
        "d) None of above"
      ],
      "answer": "C"
    },
    {
      "question": "<p>Identify the C++ compiler of Linux </p>",
      "options": ["a) - cpp ", "b)  - g++", "c) - Borland", "d)  - vc++"],
      "answer": "B"
    },
    {
      "question": "<p>] Evaluate the following Java expression, if x=3, y=5, and z=10: ++z + y - y + z + x++ </p>",
      "options": ["a) 24", "b) 23", "c) 20", "d) 25"],
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "question": "<p>Which package contains the Random class? </p>",
      "options": [
        "a) java.util package ",
        "b) java.lang package",
        "c) java.awt package ",
        "d) java.io package "
      ],
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "question": "<p>Predict the output. class Main { public static void main(String args[]) { int t; System.out.println(t); } } </p>",
      "options": [
        "a) 0",
        "b) Garbage Value ",
        "c) Compiler Error ",
        "d) Runtime Error "
      ],
      "answer": "C"
    },
    {
      "question": "<p> Which of the following is/are advantages of packages? </p>",
      "options": [
        "a) Packages avoid name clashes ",
        "b) Classes, even though they are visible outside their package, can have fields visible to packages only ",
        "c) We can have hidden classes that are used by the packages, but not visible outside.",
        "d) All of above"
      ],
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "question": "<p>Choose most appropriate statement</p>",
      "options": [
        "a)An abstract base class can have pure virtual destructor",
        "b) An abstract base class can have only virtual destructor",
        "c) An abstract base class can have non virtual destructor",
        "d) An abstract base class cannot have destructor"
      ],
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "question": "<p>Which of the following statements regarding enumerators is false?</p>",
      "options": [
        "a) Enumeration is an alternative method for naming integer constants",
        "b) An enumerator value can’t be changed in a program",
        "c) An integer value may be assigned to an enumerated variable",
        "d) An enum defined within a structure is local to the structure"
      ],
      "answer": "C"
    },
    {
      "question": "<p>Which of the following statements is false?</p>",
      "options": [
        "a) typedef defines new data types",
        "b) Using typedef does not replace the standard C++ data type name with the new name",
        "c) The new name defined by typedef, can be used as a type for another typedef",
        "d) None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "A"
    },
    {
      "question": "<p>The new operator</p>",
      "options": [
        "a) returns a pointer to the variable",
        "b) creates a variable called new",
        "c) obtains memory for a new variable",
        "d) tells how much memory is available"
      ],
      "answer": "C"
    },
    {
      "question": "<p>Which of the following concepts means adding new components to a program as it runs?</p>",
      "options": [
        "a) Data hiding",
        "b) Dynamic typing",
        "c) Dynamic binding",
        "d) Dynamic loading "
      ],
      "answer": "D"
    },
    {
      "question": "<p> In which type of storage location does the vector members are stored?</p>",
      "options": [
        "a) Contiguous storage locations",
        "b) Non-contiguous storage locations",
        "c) Both a & b",
        "d) None of the mentioned"
      ],
      "answer": "A"
    }
  ]
}
